How do you go about making a small rowboat?
We just make the small scale model and draft it from that.
Make a keel out.
You make a scale model first?
Most everybody does.
Make a scale model or else they draft them out.
Draw the model on paper, either one you want to, it doesn't matter.
How big are these scale models?
A general rule on small type.
Oh, just a three-quarter inch to a foot.
The large ones are up to a...
a quarter inch to a foot.
And what's the purpose of the scale model?
Well, the design on the length and the width and the width.
Oh, I see. They just use smaller everything and then they just scale them up and down.
And how do you go about deciding to build the boat itself?
Well, you make a keel first from the model, from the drafting, drawing for the idea.
And you had the stem, and the stern, and for the small stuff, the small boats, where you bent the frame right at it.
You make a mole, a mole, what we call a mole, so there's a section of it,
of the, get the, so far apart on the boat you take the
the shape of it, make sections.
What do they use to do that, plywood?
Plywood or cedar, either, doesn't matter.